Henry DeWolf Smyth Papers 1885-1987 Mss.Ms.Coll.15
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI. Speeches and Testimonies, 1945-1987
  - Work of the AEC. The, 1951
    - Folder #1
      program, outline, typescript
    - Folder #2
    - Folder #3
      corr.
  - Anderson, Clinton P., 6 Apr. 1956 (Box VIb. by Colleagues)
    Can we halt the race for atomic arms?
  - Bacher, Robert F., 9 Feb. 1949
    The development of nuclear reactors
  - Bacher, Robert F., 27 Mar. 1950
    The hydrogen bomb
  - Bacher, Robert F., 30 Jan. 1948
    The physicist and the future development of atomic energy
  - Bacher, Robert F., 17 Mar. 1949
    The utilization of atomic energy
  - Bishop, Amasa S., 11 Mar. 1969
    The status and outlook of the world program in controlled fusion research
    -See Ser. I, Bishop, Amasa S.
  - Borsch, Frederick H.
    -See Memorial service in thanksgiving for the life of HDS: 1898-1986. Remarks at a
  - Boskey, Bennett, 25 Apr. 1957
    Patent licensing problems in international atomic energy development
  - Bowman, Isaiah., 8 Oct. 1945
    [Federal support of scientific research]
  - Boyd, James, 22 Mar. 1960
    Nuclear explosives in mining
    -See Ser. I, Joint Committee on Atomic Energy
  - Brown, Harold, 15 Mar. 1960
    Plowshare and its scientific applications
  - Brown, J. Douglas, 2 Apr. 1948
    The Princeton pattern of a liberal education
    reprint
  - Carey, James B., Mar. 1946
    [Rollins Conference on World Government. Statement at]
  - Cisler, Walker L., 24 May 1956
    [Gore Bill-S2725]. Statement with respect to
  - Conway, John T., 14 Jun. 1966
    The role of nuclear materials management in policing a non-proliferation agreement
  - Coy, Wayne, 1 Dec. 1949
    The First Amendment to the Constitution and public interest requirements
  - Davis, W. Kenneth, 18-20 Jan. 1956
    AEC policy on reactor fuel processing
  - Davis, W. Kenneth, 7 Dec. 1956
    Chemistry and nuclear power
  - Davis, W. Kenneth, 27 Sept. 1956
    The development of nuclear power reactors
  - Davis, W. Kenneth, 29 Dec. 1955
    Industrial applications of atomic power
  - Davis, W. Kenneth, 1 Apr. 1955
    Nuclear power industry development
  - Davis, W. Kenneth, 10 Oct. 1955
    The outlook for nuclear power
  - Davis, W. Kenneth, 29 Jun. 1955
    Power reactor development in the U.S.
  - Davis, W. Kenneth, 13 Jun. 1956
    The role of nuclear power in meeting our energy needs
  - Diamond, Edward, 23 Aug. 1955
    International aspects of the U.S. atomic energy program
  - Dodds, H. W., [1955]
    [Albert Einstein. Statement on the death of]
    typescript quote
  - Donnelly, Warren H., Dec. 1983
    Verifying arms control agreements: the potential utility of the IAEA's safeguards experience and organization
    -See Ser. I, Glennan, T. Keith
  - Dunning, Gordon, 15 Nov. 1956
    Immediate radiations from a nuclear detonation
  - Durham, Carl T., 19 Mar. 1958
    Current problems in atomic power development
  - Early, Stephen T., 7 Dec. 1949
    [Remarks at Amherst College]
  - Eisenbud, Merril., 15 Nov. 1956
    Global distribution of radioactivity from nuclear detonations, with special reference to Strontium-90
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 8 Dec. 1953
    Atomic power for peace
  - Eklund, Sigvard, 13 Nov. 1981
    Armed Israeli agression against the Iraqi nuclear installations and its grave consequences for the established international system concerning the peaceful uses of nuclear energy, the nonproliferation of nuclear weapons and international peace and security
    speech to U.N.
  - Eklund, Sigvard, 13 May 1977
    International conference on nuclear power and its fuel cycle. Closing remarks
  - Eklund, Sigvard, 29 Apr. 1983
    Remarks at the celebration of Professor HDS' 85th birthday by the University of Princeton
    typescript w/HDS notes
  - Eklund, Sigvard, 22 Nov. 1966
    [Statement to the 21st session of the U.N. General Assembly]
  - Eklund, Sigvard, 4 Dec. 1970
    Statement to the 25th session of the U.N. General Assembly
    -See Ser. I, Eklund, Sigvard
  - Eklund, Sigvard, 10 Nov. 1981
    Statement to the 36th session of the U.N. General Assembly
  - Fisher, Adrian S., 9 Aug. 1966
    [Statement...at the 280th ENDC plenary meeting]
  - Fisher, Adrian S., 1976
    [Testimony... before the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations on Senate concurrent resolution 69, on nuclear reduction, testing and nonproliferation]
    -See Ser. II, Senate Committee on Foreign Relations. Subcommitte on Arms Control, International Organizations & Security Agreements. Hearing on Senate concurrent resolution 69.
  - Fitch, Val L.
  - Glennan, T. Keith, Nov. 1972
    [Speech at the joint banquet of the Atomic Industrial Forum and the American Nuclear Society]
  - Goldschmidt, B., Jan. 1967
    Text of public lecture
  - Goodman, Clark D., 30 Oct. 1956
    Nuclear materials--the bottle-neck
  - Hahn, Otto, 23 Sept. 1966
    [Fermi Award acceptance remarks]
  - Hoffman, Paul G., 18 Jan. 1950
    The Marshall plan and human rights
  - Holifield, Chet, 29 Jul. 1948
    [Remarks on the FBI and AEC clear of Dr. E. U. Condon]
  - Hunsaker, J. C., 4 Oct. 1945
    Statement... regarding S.1285, S.1248, and S.1297
  - Inouye, Goro, 17 May 1957
    The opening address [for the Conference on Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy]
  - Johnson, Jesse C., 25 Jun. 1956
    AEC's program and policies in the uranium field
  - Johnson, Jesse C., 20 Feb. 1956
    The romance of uranium
  - Johnson, Jesse C., 4 Feb. 1956
    Some comments on the uranium market
  - Johnson, Jesse C., 5 Apr. 1955
    Uranium resources for industrial power
  - Kennan, George F., 30 Apr. 1956
    [Address]
  - Kennan, George F., 3 May 1956
    Can we do better than co-exist?
  - Kennan, George F., 25 Feb. 1967
    Contribution to memorial service for J. Robert Oppenheimer
  - Kissinger, Henry A., Mar. 1976
    [Nuclear proliferation. Statement before the Senate Committee on Government Operations]
    -See Ser. II, Senate Committee on Foreign Relations. Subcommittee on Arms Control, International Organizations & Security Agreements. Hearing on senate concurrent resolution 69
  - Knowland, William F., 19 Dec. 1947
    Science and the national welfare
    -See Ser. II, Condon affair
  - Langmuir, Irving, 8 Oct. 1945
    Discussion of science legislation
  - Libby, Willard F., 21 Mar. 1956
    Atomic power
  - Libby, Willard F., 27 Apr. 1956
    Education and atomic energy
  - Libby, Willard F., 27 Apr. 1956
    Peaceful uses of atomic energy
  - Libby, Willard F., 3 Jun. 1955
    Radioactive fallout
  - Libby, Willard F., 29 Sept. 1955
  - Libby, Willard F., 19 Jan. 1956
    Radioactive fallout and radioactive strontium
    -See also Libby, Radioactive strontium fallout
  - Libby, Willard F., 20 Apr. 1956
    Radioactive strontium fallout
    -See also Libby, Radioactive fallout and radioactive strontium
  - Libby, Willard F., 10 Apr. 1956
    Radiochemistry
  - Libby, Willard F., 17 Dec. 1954
    Scientific education
  - Lichtenstein, Walter, n.d.
    Introduction of [HDS]
  - Lieberman, Joseph A., 16 Nov. 1956
    Engineering aspects of the disposal of radioactive wastes from the peacetime applications of nuclear technology
  - Lilienthal, David E., 2 Dec. 1947
    Atomic energy and the engineer
  - Lilienthal, David E., 1963
    Change, hope, and the bomb
  - Lilienthal, David E., 1963
    The mythology of nuclear disarmament
  - Lilienthal, David E., 1963
    Whatever happened to the peaceful atom?
  - McCone, John A., 13 Feb. 1959 (Box Series VI-6)
    [Testimony before the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy]
    -See Ser. III, Reactor Policies and Programs. Ad Hoc Advisory Committee on
  - McGrath, J. Howard, 1 Mar. 1950
    The meaning of freedom
  - McGovern, George, 2 Aug. 1963
    New perspectives on American security
  - McKinney, Robert, 3 Nov. 1959
    Our international atomic policies: the need for a new outlook
  - Manly, Charles G., 4 Apr. 1955
    Industrial participation
  - Manly, Charles G., 27 Jul. 1955
    [Remarks at the Machinery and Allied Products Institute meeting]
  - Manly, Charles G., 11 Oct. 1955
    [Remarks before the American Public Power Association
  - Manowitz, Bernard, 24 Mar. 1960
    The use of nuclear reactors for the production of industrial chemicals
  - Marshak, Robert Eugene, 14 Oct. 1968
    Presentation of the Atoms for Peace Award address
  - Medina, Harold R., 10 Nov. 1950
    The Princeton class: a study in democracy
    reprints
  - Memorial service in thanksgiving for the life of HDS: 1898-1986. Remarks at a, 20 Feb. 1987
    BOrsch, Frederick H.
    Fitch, Val L.
    O'Donnell, Ashton
  - Murray, Thomas E., 26 May 1955
    The atom and a new moral maturity
  - Murray, Thomas E., 21 Sept. 1954
    Atomic energy for peace
  - Murray, Thomas E., 10 Nov. 1956
    Moraligy and security-the forgotten equation
  - Murray, Thomas E., 31 Jan. 1955; 8 Feb. 1955
    [Statement at hearings before the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy]
  - Murray, Thomas E., 2 Jun. 1954
    Statement...before Joint Committee on Atomic Energy
  - Murray, Thomas E., 12 Apr. 1956
    [Statement...before the Subcommittee on Disarmament of the Committee on Foreign Relations]
  - Murray, Thomas E., 18 Jun. 1956
    [Statement...to the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy]
  - Nixon, Richard, 22 Jan. 1970
    The state of the union
    -See Ser. I, Nixon, Richard
  - O'Donnell, Ashton
    -See Memorial service in thanksgiving for the life of HDS: 1898-1986. Remarks at
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 6 Mar. 1950
    Encouragement of science
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 15 Jan. 1964
    [Introduction of HDS]
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, Aug. 1963
    Niels Bohr and his times: part III, the atomic nucleus
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 2 Dec. 1963
    [Remarks at the Enrico Fermi Award ceremony]
    -See Ser. III, [Fermi Award to Oppenheimer]
  - Osborn, Frederick, 16 May 1952
    [Address at the Princeton Graduate Council spring meeting]
  - Osborn, Frederick, 20 Mar. 1953
    Princeton today
  - Pastore, John O., 9 Mar. 1967
    Nonproliferation of nuclear weapons. Floor statement
  - Price, Harold L., 24 May 1955
    AEC licensing program
  - Price, Harold L., 27 Jun. 1956
    [Remarks...at the Governor's Conference]
  - Rabi, I. I.
  - Ramey, James T., 13 Nov. 1963
    The U.S. international atomic power program and American industry
  - Rickover, H. G., 22 Nov. 1955
    Engineering and scientific education
  - Roddis, Louis H., Jr., 29 Aug. 1956
    Impact of peaceful uses of atomic energy
  - Roddis, Louis H., Jr., 26 Apr. 1956
    Possibilities for developing small power reactors
  - Roddis, Louis H., Jr., 18 Jul. 1955
    Present status of atomic power in the U.S.
  - Rolander, C. A., Jr., 27 Oct. 1955
    Atomic industrial progress and security
  - Sachs, Alexander, 27 Nov. 1945
    Background and early history of atomic bomb project in relation to President Roosevelt
    -See Ser. I, Dodds, Harold W.
  - Seaborg, Glenn T., 4 Dec. 1963
    The Argonne accelerator-instrument and symbol of research progress
  - Seaborg, Glenn T., 14 Oct. 1971
    Brookhaven: an adventure in scientific research
  - Seaborg, Glenn T., 7 Dec. 1963
    Cooperative venture in science-model for the future
  - Seaborg, Glenn T., 19 Oct. 1967
    Future outlook for the applications of nuclear science
  - Seaborg, Glenn T., 31 Aug. 1967
    Promise of the IAEA
  - Seaborg, Glenn T., 22 Sept. 1970
    [Remarks to the 14th General Conference of the IAEA]
  - Seaborg, Glenn T., 2 Aug. 1966
    [Statement...before the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy]
    -See Ser. IV, Toll enrichment arrangements
  - Seaborg, Glenn T., Jul. 1964
    [Statement for the 8th General Conference of the IAEA]
  - Shapely, Harlow, 9 Oct. 1945
  - Shotwell, James T., 24 Jan. 1946
    The international implications of nuclear energy
  - Shotwell, James T., 1945
    Problem of security under the charter
    typescript; Carnegie Endow. for Internat. Peace
  - Spitzer, Lyman, 17 Jul. 1958
    The stellarator program [Project Matterhorn]
    -See Ser. I, Geneva Conference. Committee to read papers
  - Sprout, Harold, 19 Aug. 1945
    Princeton preceptorial of the air
    -See Ser. VIa, Princeton preceptorial of the air
  - Stassen, Harold E., 8 Nov. 1945
    [Academy of Political Science. Address at]
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 26 Apr. 1956
    Statement...on discontinuation of H-bomb tests
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 21 Nov. 1955
    Freedom's need for the trained man
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 9 Nov. 1955
    Promises and problems of nuclear power
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 20 Sept. 1956
    [Remarks at the Conference on the Statute of the IAEA]
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 6 Jun. 1955
    [Remarks to...American Medical Association]
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 21 Jan. 1956
    [Remarks...to the New Mexico Press Association]
  - Strauss, Lewis L., n.d.
    [Soviet nuclear tests]
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 15 Feb. 1955
    Statement on the AEC report on the effects of high-yield nuclear explosions
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 4 Jun. 1954
    Statement to the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 10 Feb. 1955
    [Statement to the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy]
  - Sykes, Lyn R., 20 Nov. 1985
    Verification of a comprehensive nuclear test ban treaty, Soviet compliance with the threshold test ban treaty, and the sizzles of Soviet strategic nuclear weapons
    testimony
  - Taplin, Frank E., 4 Nov. 1970
    Y.M.C.A. Executive Club...introduction of HDS
  - Teller, Edward, 22 Mar. 1960
    Summary of plowshare program
  - Thornton, C. D. W., 25 Oct. 1971
    Setting new standards for safeguarding the peaceful atom
  - Travers, W. J., 22 Mar. 1960
    Project Oilsand
    -See Ser. I, Joint Commission on Atomic Energy
  - Usmani, I. H., 19 Mar. 1963
    Science for survival
  - Vallarta, Manuel Sandoval, 22 Feb. 1967
    [Oppenheimer. Statement to the IAEA Board of Governors on]
  - Vance, Harold S., 26 Sept. 1956
    International nuclear power--a challenge to the U.S.
  - Van der Meulen, P. A., 8 Nov. 1956
    Our plans for a nuclear science center at Rutgers
  - Webster, William, 24 May 1956
    [Gore Bill-S2725. Statement on]
  - Weinberg, Alvin M., 27 May 1958
    Long-range approach to nuclear reactor development
    -See Ser. III, Reactor Policies and Programs, Ad Hoc Committee on
  - Ziesing, Hibben, 1979
- Series VII. Manuscripts of Unpublished Works by HDS, 1914-15; 1941-74
  contains notes, outlines, reviews, and autograph and typescript drafts generated by Smyth during his years of involvement with Princeton University, the National Defense Research Committee (NDRC), and the Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD). Writings are arranged alphabetically by title. The earliest material in this series is Smyth's 1914 high school paper entitled "Sea power in the American Revolution."
  Of interest are two chapters of his autobiography which concern his childhood and some of his experiences in World War II. A large number of items are draft reports for the NDRC and the OSRD, some of which concern the peacetime plans for the Development of Substitute Materials (DSM). There is a draft history of the preparation of the Smyth Report and many drafts having to do with secrecy. The latest material in the series consists of his 1974 drafts, notes and correspondence on the "History of the H-Bomb."
  - [Analysis of computer situation at Princeton], 1958 (Box Series VII-1)
    John von Neumann's MANIAC computer
  - Atomic bomb, The, n.d.
  - Atomic Energy Commission's contracts with universities: a statement of policy, 15 May 1950
  - Autobiographical essays, topics, n.d.
  - [Autobiography], n.d.
    autograph: chron.; family background; forest, mountain, a field
  - [Autobiography: experiences in World War II: Berkeley, bullets and bombs], 1974
  - Bridgeman, P. W. "Reflections of a physicist" for American Scientist, n.d.
    review
  - Classics, The, 1915
    autograph, re: classical education
  - [Comments on "The Bomb Is out" by Mr. Hutchins which appeared in the American magazine], 1 Dec. 1947
    -See Ser.I, Conant, James B.
  - Comments on the IAEA, 8 Aug. 1961
    -See Ser.I, Rusk, Dean
  - Comments on the role assigned to the IAEA in ACDA draft paper, n.d.
  - Construction of the NDRC experimental firing range at Princeton University
    -See Report on the construction of a small arms experimental range at Princeton University
  - Cost of secrecy, 27 Dec. 1948
  - European trip report on EURATOM, OEEC and IAEA, Aug.-Sep. 1959
  - History of the H-Bomb
    Armstrong, Hamilton Fish
    McMahon, Brien
    Manley, J. H.
    -See also Ser.VIa, Hydrogen bomb development in the U.S.
    - Folder #1, 1949-74
      notes, drafts
    - Folder #2, 1959-60
      corresp.
  - History of the preparation of my report on Atomic energy for military purposes, Memorandum on the, 1947
  - [Indian nuclear explosion]
    -See Ser.II, Indian Nuclear Explosion
  - [ Life magazine article], 1946
    Thorndike, Joseph J., Jr.
    effects of atomic energy
  - Manhattan Project - Isotope separation, n.d.
  - National Defense Research Committee...Contract NDRCrc-121. Proposals submitted to the Uranium Committee, 7 July 1941
  - National Defense Research Committee...Contract NDCrc-121. Reports, 1941
  - Peace time plans for the DSM projects. Preliminary draft, 8 Jan. 1944
    Development of Substitute Materials project
  - Peacetime plans for the DSM projects. Preliminary reports, 15 Mar. 1944
    DSM, Metallurgical Lab.
  - Princeton University OSRD contract OEMsr-297. Final report, Oct. 1943
    drafts re: uranium isotope separation
  - Princeton University OSRD project OEMsr-297. Memo. for members of S-1 Executive Committee, 13 Jan. 1943
    re: isotope separation
  - Problem of secrecy, 20 Feb. 1947
  - Problem of secrecy and the future of the DSM project, 1945
    -See also Ser. II, Tolman Committee...
  - Report on the construction of a small arms experimental range at Princeton University, 30 April 1941
    NDRC firing range
  - Research at Princeton, 11 Oct. 1961
  - Science and the federal government, 1958
  - Sea power in the American revolution, 7 May 1914
    autograph, [high school paper?]
  - Seventy years of physics at Princeton, n.d.
    -See also Ser.II, Physics at Princeton
    autograph drafts
  - Small chain reacting units, 5 Dec. 1945
    State Dept.
  - Small power units, 5 Dec. 1945
  - Source material on small "piles" or nuclear reactors, 7 Dec. 1945
  - State Department. Memorandum of negotiations with the, May-Jul. 1947
    scientific mission to London
  - [Stonehenge, remarks on], n.d.
    autograph
- Series VIII. Manuscripts of Published Works by HDS, 1919-77
  contains autograph and typescript drafts, notes, outlines and printers' proofs. Relevant correspondence having to do with some items has been kept in this series when appropriate. Some items have both Smyth's marginalia and that of other editors. The earliest piece in this series is Smyth's 1919 paper "Radiating Potentials of Nitrogen." Perhaps the most important writings in this series are the drafts of Smyth's "Dissenting Opinion...in the Matter of J. Robert Oppenheimer." The early drafts bear little resemblance to the final of this statement which includes revisions throughout the day and night of 29 June 1954. Also significant are the drafts of "The Need for International Safeguards" which discuss the role of safeguards in inhibiting the spread of nuclear weapons in the context of the Nonproliferation Treaty. The most recent items in the series are the drafts of "The `Smyth Report,' " a history which was published in the Princeton University Library Chronicle.
  - Article for Alumni Weekly, n.d. (Box Series VIII-1)
    Princeton physics dept.
  - Atomic research center at Brookhaven, 14 April 1947
    -See Ser.II, Brookhaven National Laboratory #2
    foreward to Byrd Hopkins' Princeton engineer art.
  - Critical potentials of molecular hydrogen, 1927
    -See also Ser.IX, Condon, E. U. Critical potentials of molecular hydrogen
  - Dissenting opinion of HDS in the matter of J. Robert Oppenheimer, 1954
    Vogel, Clark C.
    -See also Ser.I, Oppenheimer
    Security Clearance
    -See also Ser.IX, U.S. AEC. In the matter of J. Robert Oppenheimer...
    in U.S. AEC "Statement by the AEC"; autograph and typescript drafts
    - Folder #1, 21 May-10 Jun. 1954
      outline, chronology
    - Folder #2, 14-16 Jun.
      re: General Manager's memo. of 12 Jun. 1954
    - Folder #3, 17 Jun.
    - Folder #4, 18 Jun.
      procedure and admin. practice
    - Folder #5, 20 Jun.
      secrecy
    - Folder #6, 21 Jun.
    - Folder #7, 22 Jun.
    - Folder #8, 23 Jun.
    - Folder #9, 24 Jun.
    - Folder #10, 25 Jun.
      new outline
    - Folder #11, 26 Jun.
    - Folder #12, 27 Jun.
    - Folder #13, 28 Jun.
    - Folder #14, 29 Jun. 1954 (Box Series VIII-2)
      final drafts
    - Folder #15, n.d.
      outlines, notes, drafts
  - Effect of fluorescence and dissociation on the ionizing potential of iodine vapor Compton, K[arl] T[aylor], 1920
    notes, autograph mss.
  - Federal support of research in science and engineering at Princeton, 1959
    Alumni Weekly article
  - Industrial application of atomic energy, Jun. 1954
    -See also Ser. VIa, Industrial application of atomic energy
  - Keynote Editorial. Journal of reactor science and technology, 1 Jan. [ca. 1951]
    outline, drafts re: publication & secrecy
  - Need for international safeguards
    Bechhoefer, Bernard G.
    Gilinsky, Victor
    Hargrove, John Lawrence
    Leachman, Robert
    Szasz, Paul
    Willrich, Mason
    in Int'l Safeguards & Nuclear Indust. drafts, corresp.
    - Folders #1-3, 1971
    - Folders #4-5, 1972
    - Folder #6, 1972 (Box Series VIII-3)
  - Radiating potentials of nitrogen Compton, Karl [Taylor], 1919
    mss., corresp.
  - Research in science and engineering, 15 May 1959
    Alumni Weekly article, re: Princeton
  - Smyth Report. Memoranda, 1944
    notes on visits to Conant, Briggs, Urey, Lavender; & on Breit notebooks
  - "The `Smyth Report' "
    Bailey, Herbert
    Coleman, Earl E.
    Hewlett, Richard G.
    O'Leary, Jean M.
    Parish, W. A., Jr.
    Reuben, Walter
    Shurcliff, William
    Smyth, Mary deC.
    Thompson, James S.
    -See also Ser. IX, Princeton
    University Library Chronicle
    Princeton Univ. Lib. Chronicle article
    - Folder #1, 1973-75
      notes by HDS & MdeCS, corresp.
    - Folders #2-3, 1975
      corresp., drafts
    - Folders #4-5, 1976
    - Folder #6, 1976-77; n.d.
  - Some comments on the Lilienthal Report
    -See Stopping the atomic armament race: what we are up against
  - Stopping the atomic armament race:
    what we are up against
    Cloud, Dudley
    Weeks, Edward
    Atlantic Monthly article
    - Folders #1-2, 1946
      autograph draft, page proofs
- Series IX. Reprints, Journals and Publications, 1913-85
  contains reprints, reports, journal issues, photocopies and typescripts of scientific papers, and reviews prepared by Smyth's colleagues. Notes, data and abstracts of these papers are included as well. The series is organized alphabetically by author name, or by title when the author is unknown. Smyth's reprints appear in this series rather than with his manuscripts of published works (Series VIII). Complete journal issues have been treated in one of two ways: if the article of interest to Smyth was indicated, the issue was entered under the article's author; if no article was marked or the entire issue seemed to be of interest, the issue was entered under the journal title.